# CHRISTOPHER JANSEN

2383 Akers Mill Rd, Atlanta, GA, 417-299-9027, <a href="mailto:com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com">christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com</a>, <a href="https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com">https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com</a>, <a href="mailto:https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com">https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com</a>, <a href="mailto:https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com">https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmail.com</a>, <a href="mailto:https://github.com/christopherbraggiansen@gmailto:https://github.com/c

## **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Software Developer with over five years of career experience in the technology field. Developed multiple production backend applications and scripts in a variety of languages. Strong understanding of servers and I.T. operations. Lifelong learner willing to adapt to new challenges excited to learn about new technologies.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Infrastructure Specialist

June 2018 - June 2019

- Berea College | Berea, KY
- Responsible for operation, maintenance and backup of 185 mission critical servers.
- Developed multiple new scripts in Python and rewrote and modified existing PowerShell scripts to automate repetitive tasks saving time and money.
- Collaborated with multiple departments to analyze their technical requirements, and design and implement systems which meet these requirements in a cost efficient and timely manner.
- Documented current and desired future configurations processes, policies and topologies and trained new staff members on these aspects.
- Identified and fixed challenging problems involving servers, applications, databases, networking, and scripts improving the stability of infrastructure and user experience.

# Technical Support Specialist/ Software Developer Berea College | Berea, KY

June 2017 - May 2018

- Designed, developed and tested a RESTful API inventory control application in python which eliminated the need for manual paperwork, reduced errors, and increased efficiency.
- Managed the help desk work order system to ensure that accurate tickets existed for every issue and that every ticket was delegated to a technician with appropriate skill level.
- Provided technical support, diagnostics, and troubleshooting by phone, in person, and through email for Windows, network issues, and a wide range of hardware, software, and cloud services.
- Supervised, trained, and provided daily guidance to junior staff on technical and policy issues insuring professional and timely completion of all assignments.

# **Computer Science Teaching Assistant**

January 2016 - December 2016

# Berea College | Berea, KY

- Mentored undergraduate students one-on-one on computer science topics and coding to improve their problemsolving skills, help them achieve a deep understanding and to develop as enthusiastic lifelong learners.
- Researched, organized, and implemented complex projects involving hardware and coding, including gathering and ordering inventory, developing sample code, and writing detailed technical documentation.
- Evaluated software options for classes including appropriate Linux distributions, desktop software, and cloud solutions.

#### Software Development Intern

#### June 2016 - August 2016

## Berea College | Berea, KY

- Engaged in .NET web application development (using C#, ASP.NET, and Microsoft SQL) for a campus wide, mission critical application which is still in use and maintained today.
- Fixed existing issues and brought code in line with industry best practices involving quality, speed, reliability, and security, which resulted in a 75% reduction in load times.
- Designed, coded, tested, documented, and released new code and bug fixes to meet customer requirements within specific deadlines using agile development principles.

## **Desktop Support Technician**

January 2016 - June 2016

#### Berea College | Berea, KY

- Supported facility, staff, and students with software, hardware, and network issues by troubleshooting and making appropriate changes, repairs and replacements.
- Worked with the desktop support team to support and train over twenty Help Desk Technicians.

### Help Desk Technician

August 2013 - August 2014

#### Berea College | Berea, KY

- Provided technical support in person and by phone for a campus of over 2000.
- Worked with a team to catalog and resolve issues and manage computer inventory.
- Learned and followed I.T. best practices appropriate to higher educational institution.

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Arts in Computer & Information Science Berea College, Berea, KY

December 2016

Full tuition scholarship, Graduated Cum Laude, Dean's List